Let's see if we can do that.
Okay, discussion.
I'm going to start with CW.
I'm going to start with the training method.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah?
Oh.
So, the easier one.
Take my speed to my speed stats.
Yeah, go ahead.
I've looked at that very closely.
Yeah?
I have very detailed notes.
Okay.
Alex is there.
Is that it?
Well, you can say the second, okay?
Alex?
I hear you.
Okay, of course.
So, according to Alex, just so you know, yeah?
Yeah, yeah, sure.
I will just mainly listen
and I don't know how much time
I really got.
My daughter wakes up, I have to take care of her.
We understand.
It's all cool.
Yeah, because I'll use this transcription then,
like you'll get it to be auto transcribed.
And then you can...
Yeah, sure.
You can turn on the light
so that Claude can better see.
I should have just let Claude join this meeting there.
Yeah.
Well, the telecom said
that they will put
the chatbot
or AI into their
into their landline.
No, mobile line.
And then...
But you can request it in the beginning
of the call
or at the end you can ask for summary
and stuff like that
or ask questions during the call.
What?
Lightly...
concerning.
Okay, well, good.
I think it's already clear that this is not possible.
Impossible.
You'd have to opt in
actually with an in signature, I think.
I think that's the only way.
Both parties, absolutely.
Yeah, good.
Yeah, I think...
I thought that the best way maybe is
that I show you
just a short sketch of the proof
I have for positive semi-definite
matrices because it's...
I would say it's pretty much straight forward.
And
you have to say, I mean, we can start
with the problem of just feasibility
because optimality
just comes with another
with an additional constraint
like I said.
It's most
more or less the same thing.
The simplest thing first.
Okay, so let's say
I don't want to...
Okay.
Let's say we have some
set C
and
that is X
I will write this populist
you just...
make it too complex
and
we will also get it from
reals to complex numbers.
Just one check.
We have to change one number.
These are real positive
symmetric.
Let's start by real positive symmetric
matrices.
Well, yeah.
And what we're looking for
is that they
obey
some
positive relations
for all I
and...
Yeah.
Yeah, so you can write it as trace
it's just because I was too lazy
at some point to always write trace.
And
so we can write X of A
which...
When we go to...
Okay, maybe you're right.
Yeah.
Just stick with this for now.
Just stick with this because in the end
it becomes kind of important.
So, and the proof is
as I said is pretty much straightforward.
We assume
that there is...
this
X
element C
such that
the
rank
of X
equals R.
So
what it follows from this is that
you can write X
as B
that one
positive definite.
So it's a material.
Clear?
And by the way
you can also determine these
up front if you know.
Do you want the Vs to be R by N matrices now?
Yeah.
So,
some
are N matrix
and they are
like...
You can see this
pretty fast.
They are orthogonal to the kernel
of X of R.
The columns of it are
some vectors that
span all following the company.
And so when you're here
you can
you can define
how we will
define
the problem in a hat
is equal to
VT
VI
V
and therefore
any feasible X
can be written
as
AI
equals
VI. So we know
that this is true
and since this
is feasible we will
define another function
and
I will just
call this function
PI and
it goes
from the symmetric
R by R matrices
to
the
space RR. This
composition is being recorded on Zoom
just so you know.
And each
like
this five takes in
a second
some
V
and the I component of it
is simply
AI
V
and now it's pretty much straightforward.
You know from
from the rank
nullity
theorem
you know that
the
value
that
difference
in R
must be equal
to
the
random
five
of
the
image fine
and
you know that
this is equal to
the real dimension of it
R times
R plus one over two
and you know that
the image of
five
I have to check something this is
sorry this is not R this is N
and
so well now it depends
on how these
type of things that
are defined by the AI
within the
ambience space but you can say that this
is at most M.
So what you see from here is
that
the dimension
of
serial I
and
must be
here
and
so
this means
if this is
a number that is larger
or equal larger equal than one
and you will always
find some dB
so
if R
is R plus one over two
minus M is larger equal
one
there it lists
and
that is not zero
such that
the operator
B over T equals
B
plus two
and
that is five
almost right
so what this means
is
you will find
a sufficiently small T
such that
BT becomes
similar
and so you can reduce the rank
by one
and you can do this
as long as
rank
R by one
and you can do this
as long as the kernel
is larger equal to one
and so that is why
that is why we have this
this
which says that
R
R plus one over two
must be smaller
than
M or in the complex case
you can just
replace everything
that R
is smaller than that
strictly greater than
rank double these here
so if I just move the image
to the left hand side
isn't this
you assume R
right
and this is
just M by one
so why is it
strictly greater than
any
or am I
you only can
bound the term by a smaller
equals
in which case
is that
right now
so the plastic example then is the rank one
right
so
M is one
we know that the rank is
you told us this cool thing
where you got one constraint
and the rank or even two constraints
so you can see
this is
definitely true
I'm sure about that one
so what you can see from here
this is just a feasibility thing
and so
this means
so R can be
you can just check it
in that case
for the
for the complex
case
everything when M
is
less than four
always find the rank one
so up to three is fine
and for real
you can just check
that this is for
for M
that's good
and now I told you this the logic is
there exists D not equal to zero
such that BT be satisfied
with the constraints
the point is
if I have
maybe not
it's obvious but maybe not
if this is
larger or equal than one
I can always
from the kernel
then maybe this
D is from the kernel
that makes
okay
and then I can
then I can just
take any kind of addition
and it still satisfies
the constraints
and from the continuity
of the eigenvalues
we know that
there will be some sufficiently small T
maybe I should write it like this
such that BT becomes similar
but then you are actually
you know
you take the characteristic polynomial
and then it has roots
the sufficiently small doesn't smell right
why is T
to be small
I'd rather expect T to be quite large
ah okay
if you take
the point of it
there you've got a polynomial
in T
and by the fundamental theorem of algebra
we've got
I think that's what you're saying
that's just
I think
the picture that T
already has in mind is your increased T
until you get to
when it gets to existence it's kind of tricky
because then right over the real numbers
they might be having number roots
right
after the real game
so to complex
I'm happy with it
but the fundamental theorem of algebra
in this big field
which the real numbers are
and in fact I think you want
because it really could be right
the T of A is the polynomial
x squared plus 3 is 0
which you can't do
I cannot
I think that there's something more going on
isn't there
yeah it's not the character of the polynomial
but T is not the
I don't know
yeah I mean I put it in the
generalized eigenvalue version
of this what do you call that
not character of the polynomial
generalized character is probably
probably right
and so
yeah
there's something else going on
like
you can I mean
isn't the idea that you add T and it's bigger and bigger and bigger
and then you're going to go in
feasible at some point
no this is the whole point
it's in the kernel of phi
the point is phi is a linear function
phi is linear
and because of that
I can take this ring now
and I can see
that I can take some D
which is in the
like it's in the
it's in the kernel of this function
which means it does not
it does not alter
the outcome of the
of the constraints
that's true
but what's the
story of T then
it selects the right T
that
thing becomes singular
singularity means
the determinant is zero
yeah I mean T most lambs
you can always find a T that makes one of
the eigenvalues zero
whereas previously it was a strictly positive
matrix phi
I find a T so that you reduce the rank
yeah but can T go infinitely negative
but why can you find
a D that compensates
for an eigenvalue
it's somehow
circling around that maybe
I think this is the
the constraint
that Tobias mentioned
we made that argument
but it's different
with some
but
I'm going to try to
do you
mean that I can reduce to the
top state
and then
then you turn
one of the same
I'm not
sure if you know what you're doing
but what we're basically doing up there
with the center now we are
moving from
I'm not sure if you know what I'm talking about
so this A that is
the same old story of
by leading up form
to its
reproducing current
can I just push the determinant
argument through and see where it breaks
we shouldn't need anything to match it right
like we're saying
so we're saying the B
term and then the same
I think you want to
factor out B because it's invertible
you can make it into a characteristic
polynomial of
square root inverse B
D square root inverse B
and then also one of our
T
so then you're arguing that
there exists a T
which makes this thing
okay for complexity
it's fine
complexity but even for real T
because
yeah
so D is not positive
D can be any evolution
anything just not zero
so you put the T as
the D
we'll try to make it without
the point is
is that D can have negative i
that's allowed
and now as soon as a negative i
is positive
I can't buy it now
okay
and this is the whole proof
for it
how do you
argue that
so there exists a T
such as P0
P0 is singular and so because
rank was an R
but how do you argue that
right because that's the argument
and we say that there is some B of P0
which is singular so it does
rank one less and we say that
that's our new feasible solution
it's a flexible string but you also need the positive
D is in the column of 5
so it's a symmetric matrix
symmetric so you can
always choose it to be
whatever you want basically
if it's in the column of 5
it's either positive, it's fully positive
in which case you put a minus sign in front of it
or it's
it will neither be positive nor
neither positive nor negative in which case
you just find the smallest eigenvalue of it
and then put a minus sign in front of that
and then you can always
zero off at least
I think the argument is right
which has
a largest
negative eigenvalue
everything is negative
and it's strictly negative
not
how do you know
oh I think it's not the number of minus signs
what if it's neither
no that's the idea
how about I just write it out
here
it has some smallest eigenvalue
some
some eigenvalue
more than two
whatever right, symmetric
and then these D's
we'll just put them in D semi-water
right
so what if they're all positive
then we put a minus sign
in front of it
there exists a D in the column
so I'm allowed to multiply by minus one
now the largest
the largest negative eigenvalue
which is T just right
I'll zero off one of the
the corresponding eigenvector
of that identity
and the other state positive
the objective here isn't
is just to zero off at least one eigenvector
of that program matrix
I think we know but also the
resulting B of T has to be positive
and it would be
why
because you just
it's not sufficiently small
it's supposed to
sufficiently small because
yeah, thanks
you just take the
the eigenvalue of T with
with the smallest absolute
value
and the smallest absolute value
well then just if it's
minus or plus you decide
why I have a T because the T can be anything
from R
and then you just push it
until that one
eigenvalue cancels
the smallest eigenvalue
of the B for example
you just in the column
here for example
if you already rank
deficient then it's fine
if not in the strict interior
then you can push it in direction
and this leaves you in a
column at least for small t
and you will reach the boundary
but it doesn't matter with which matrix
you add because in order to
say
sufficiently small t in the column
then it's already fine
then you walk to another phase
no that's not possible
because the phase is defined
by the AIs or the
the intersection of the phase
of the affine subspace
oh
yes
still
like B can have mixed eigenvalues
which are both positive and negative
we first of all cannot choose that because
the kernel can be one-dimensional
and we're just fixed with this kind of distribution of signs
then flip all signs
well we can flip all of them but it's some of them are positive
some are negative
but this
but there are one
let's say the positive signs
the positive signs
they do not work because they just make
B more positive
then it's already
possible
you don't take the most negative sign
yes
you just walk gradually t up until
it hits the first zero crossing
imagine like you perturb B by D
and for very small t
sure
values hardly change
so you can now make a plot
where you plot the curves of eigenvalues
and then you increase t this will give continuous functions
and at some point the lowest one will cross zero
and then you stop
and then you still have a positive operate
okay
but I would want that to
but
optimization
I mean here it's just inverse function theorem
I think
okay
what's your favorite proof of the inverse function theorem
non-trivial
so we have
let's say with a feasible
X
right this is your
this is your assumption
and it's offering
R
and now
that's an assumption
no because that just means
you have given the name to the rank of X
you just named the rank
you would find R to be the rank
okay
I have my problem I take one thing to the point
which says rank R
now I write my
rank R thingy as well
something from the other dimension of space
transformation
now I can write
the whole thing
now I can take the
transformation and write this whole
thing
as optimization in the subspace
R
and B is basically
you give me some C
so I have a smaller space
okay so far so good
now next step why do I define this
by
some story
I can define
maybe you don't need it but for me it was
very
intuitive to then work with the rank
now to theorem because it's just simple
so now I am in the
okay I have to take the
subspace
I could optimize it in the subspace
what do I learn but I also
have to optimize over all B
now you start with something
you start with some feasible point
you go to the sort of compressed
STP
you look at the feasible subspace
and D at the orthogonal
subspace to the feasible subspace
which is the kernel
of this file
and now you say you can always
walk in this direction to reduce the rank
by one
to the point
you start with the feasible point
then if this condition there holds
then you can find a perturbation
which reduces the rank
now you have a new feasible point
and you can redo the whole program
this was
like a while loop
so yeah
and this is awesome in this introduction
and this is also what I wanted to do
because I think this proof is
somewhat constructive not like the
pataki proofs they are all like
very static
you have some things that you have worked through
but this one is like
if you want you could check all of those
points and
reduce
the complex
pataki is still a bit different
it uses that you can do some other
tricks I don't know if you know about
the balanced
the balanced distribution
of
I don't think we want to know about that
so I'm kind of bugged by this
V, this V appears and disappears
it's a horribly
basis thinking I don't like that
can you just skip the V
well the V
the V is just
actually just the basis
of the RR
and
where this comes from
in your proof
just strike those lines up
I don't need them
I need it to
to
reduce
to get from
N to PSDR
we need it
we want to compress
if X is a state
you want to compress to support
subspace of the state
we need to choose a basis
we can throw it
we don't need to choose a basis and throw it out
I'm just being pedantic
but this is the kind of thing where
in formalization
it's a pain in the ass to choose a basis
formalize and throw it out again
so I'm just sensitive to this
okay we are fine
good
do we agree
does it pass it?
I have a feasible point
but I want to
okay so
this is actually
like you could say
we could substitute this line
by saying
each phase
of the
each phase of the PSD
end code is isomorphic
to
PSDR somewhere
that's much better because I'm also thinking
infinite dimensional here
if you want to generalize this stuff
if you want to generalize this
you don't want to be choosing V
V is okay
because it's a support
it's Henriksen
when you want to start
V, V transpose
which is really the supporting protection
it's not going to throw spaces in the support
and that's
right yeah thanks
but actually
I'm
do you really want that in infinite dimension
because if you're on a c-star algebra
this board is somewhere outside
of the c-star algebra maybe
yeah now I'm already
wondering ahead as it
was
so if this proof kind of looks okay
then we can already
the point of talking is
how far does it go
before I just
I already did a B
for my son
and what it says is that if you have
an interior point of a PSD code
you fix a random or any
direction in the operator
space and you walk along the direction
at some point you're going to be outside of the code
because then you at some point have to hit
a phase and we are just
that's the singularity here
and this just means that the code
is pointed
pointed current yeah yeah this holds
for any pointed code okay that's
actually that's very important comment right
in fact
the whole proof
can go through for just a
intermediate space
except for you have to replace rank with like
is an element of phase
and then I can find a smaller phase
they are not numbered by range
because they are in horizon orbit
because we lost the representation in terms of operators
but you can just say like the phase
of it I mentioned below
a code you mentioned
this is also one thing
why I have
another proof of that one
because I tried to do it in the first place
I learned at last now but
I have a proof that is
for an arbitrary
phone
just for
for an Archimedia that's the point here
yeah
what does that really mean
there is inside a cone
you add a little bit
yeah well for every element
of the phase
there are the
t and the t such that
t plus is in the cone
yeah
it's literally dump condition you want
so but now
and then so the
one thing that works with PSD is that
faces
a complex combination of extreme points
and extreme points of rank 1 projections
and so that's how we connect rank
to
to whatever
the constraints right and the minute we
lose representations
star representations
on some Hilbert space
the minute we can't say the word rank any longer
then we lose that rank
right is this what's happening
it's very very rank but the connection
to operate is lost if you don't
have a star representation
so
well
even though you can get
you want to get
a new space
might be
a general space
I think
if we want to see the words
operators we need some kind of representation
to say that it's not going to work
for any point in the cone
well
you can find an operator representation
but I can put this theorem
the thing that dies
is
this won't be the same right
we have to replay the rank first
the thing is that you replace that r
r plus 1 divided by 2 by the dimension
of the face
is the face
it's literally the dimension of sin
r which is just
the span of psd r
you're just saying that you replace that
explicit r expression
with the dimension of the
fine span of the face
but the connection to
operate is right you don't have
oh no then you just need to plug in the formula part
the dimension of the face
that's the only comment
I wonder if
in the other way
then we get some
over the
chain's weight or something like that
because
those are just that
they're just those r squares
some of them and you have
irreducible representation so their dimension
is just kind of the diagonal
and it's just that right
okay
then we have to put on the
that dimension
I don't know
those are
we have a cone
and
okay psd cone generalizes
for some states
the cone
any areas for this right
any
okay so we have a cone and we have
a linear optimization of the cone
this is how it would start
yeah
you could do this
T walking so you push
the salt to the edge
no next step would be well we want to
write this cone as an image
of some
some other cone
right that's what's happening here
this VBV
let's see the first line is saying
you are inside of some face
oh yeah
now
you just blink to the face
everything
that would be the
the sign dimension of face
would be r right
no that would be the
the second line
this would be okay
yeah I know I got it
actually you can project
you can project to a subspace of a face
but this is not something to be well
defined and you don't have to be able to
cleanly project the whole cone into a face
so I would just say like we are in a face
it's
like trying to redefine
these for arbitrary cone might be
I would rather not do that
than just be in a face
like because if the face can be
smaller the cone can be bigger than the
projected around the face and try to squeeze it
this would be
probably because you can do that
this part
the A heads just the projections
of the A's to the face
this is like a one column proof
for what?
one column proof
in PRA format
okay
now here's the challenge
can we make a one page PRL
what's the
tpt's baby
it's like
because
this is referring to a very old
challenge
there's a standing challenge
amongst the theoretical physics community
which is a one page PRL
published
there is a one page in each paper
shouldn't this be
the application
it doesn't need to fit the application
in the other column
it's a tricky bit
the obvious
application would always be something like
a restrictive concept problem
which is kind of
just too boring right that cone is easy
why do all this
in a continuous
area of blah blah blah
I'm thinking more like GPT
something right
we're not talking just about quantum
mechanics here we're talking about
even in post-process
but
that's for a simple
I know this cone is boring
but if I give you a
restrictive grand state problem
on some internet dimension blah blah blah
and I prove that the optimal solution will be still
pure state
I know that all those pure state variation
I met this bull still has a chance to find out
I'm not surprised by that
I don't know why but I don't know
but if I have as many constraints
it will fail
like
we can see restricted grand state would be mean actually
give me like minimum the energy
such that the angular momentum
will be bigger
number
and the energy
should also be
equal to 5
now you have your 3
I like the angular momentum angle that works
or energy or whatever
ok we have the identity, we have the Hamiltonian
want to optimize and now we have
a third that we can pick
to make this have real bite
now it would be a non-commuting
constraint for Hamilton
not some boring conservative quantity
yeah
and to have a bite
it would have to look great
because if you add just one more constraint
it does go next
that would make it really interesting
now take your favorite pure state
automation
well
which
should be 20 right
some Monte Carlo wave function
everything that has wave function
everything that seems pure state is dead
and now we can
show that it will still work here
yeah
but
no
this is not
but since you are talking about
optimization problems
this becomes just one NMR
we want to optimize
so if you have an optimization
that would directly get
something like
minus and X
then you can get a plus point
from the T
another constraint
you can see it from
so plus
you can see it from two directions
you can either say
ok we have some
some X
of red
on some face
of the C because we know that the maximum
minimum
will appear on the face
this means
this function
also needs to satisfy
CD
equals zero because
if it does not equal zero you can
take the same argument as here and argue that the point
that you found is not optimal
and
yeah
Mr. Weed linear
you know it would be cool
if you are optimizing a non-linear function
you know it could be
not too great
like entropies and stuff
you said also yesterday
that we get the problem with the regularity
if we are into information
oh yeah I didn't understand
ok
we have
one with a high R
can have
a high M constraint
for
two for the complexes
we can have two constraints
one of the constraints
one
one constraint
that means the Hamiltonian
because Hamiltonian optimization would be
H is the energy
Traces the other one
we have one free
and it still rank one
oh yeah
ok so
that's the angular momentum thing
that's the problem if you do something
and you stop maybe then
you have a worse bond
maybe you lose that one extra constraint
it's you know
rank nullity is just
more inverse function
is
implicit function theorem stuff
that it is exactly linear
but
if we go to
to the
if you have a magnetic field
that breaks angular momentum
total angular momentum is no longer conserved
when you have a magnetic field
you have an atom in a magnetic field
right now we've already
ok ground state is pure
cool we know that
put a hydrogen atom in a magnetic field
that's great
but
that's another way
to add a constraint
now you want to
you say
the perturbation breaks
the angular momentum
so now you want to fix angular momentum
despite this
you want to
ah
you want to conserve that angular momentum
you want to prescribe that
prescribe the angular momentum
yeah right
then you can also prescribe
like this
yeah
prescribes it
that's physics now right
the hydrogen atom
it's in a magnetic field
you want to push it down to the ground state
you want to say ah
I want to make sure that the total
the magnetic field points in that way
I want to make sure the total angular momentum is fixed by some number
now you
the angular momentum is in a different direction
in a different direction is fixed
cool
but then why do you care
because
you have lots of them
that becomes a bit of an issue
if you have too much angular momentum
the box is in the direction
you measure A
you put it down
the other quantity
so that's the kind of example that I think could
make it physically very interesting
you think about
what are the quantities in physics
there's more than just angular momentum
we have momentum
energy
rapidity
these are the standard conserves
then we have PC and T but they're discreet
then we have
sorry
yeah right
we could go orbital right
yeah
fusible ones must be mixed
I think that's interesting
the minute you
what would shock
a condensed matter theory is
if they're forced to use pure states
it's not allowed to use pure states
and what would shock a quantum computing person
what do you mean I can't use
quiscate with pure states
I always assumed that that was fine
most people
in this group here
mixed states are kind of like
we will understand
but that's not the majority
view here in the world
well I can tell
I know from
discussions at least at IEEE
where there were many people from IBM
they were like and I was asking the question
if anyone considers mixed states
they were like well we don't need mixed states
that's just noise
we think of ideal
quantum computers
and then every time the question happens
and no I had like three or four talks
I was attending and they were saying
there was some interesting
it was interesting
to see that our method got better
when we introduced noise to the picture
so maybe this is also a way to pick up
the interesting question is not so much
really the rank that you need
but the rank that you need
is a certain error
I mean the rank is super unstable
you can always make it
so they say okay you tell me
I need full rank but if I can approximate
the tool
after precision by pure state
but this shouldn't
just it could be robust
of course
there is only one
x that's a final
sorry I think there was a little bit of this problem
let's start with some feasible set
and start the positive
point is that
are the extreme points of this feasible set
really in the interior
or can they always be expanded
out to the community
and touch the boundaries
and somehow natural
if I only have one type of plane
I have to cut through
to a state
this is the weird bit for me
I find this very strange
this is some of the geometry and now it's also quite
if I had tool
it's hard to draw
full dimension
you have a feasible set
but it's something
and you cut your first type of plane
it's clear that you're always
on the outside
but then you cut the second type of plane
it really gets inside the base
because this is triangular face
and if I cut my second type of plane
like this
then I'm stuck inside the triangular face
but I don't want any of it
I have to fix up all of this
if you do a bit of something too
I know I remember all of this stuff
that's right
I'm sure you can stop all of this
whatever
I need another cut
and you're in the interior
it's fine
it's a better picture
I can cut right in the middle
that's true
you have one point
on the inside of the house
it's okay
okay
okay, so now I have to cut
it's zero
I have to cut the
screen point of the other
next to the rail
this is what it said
there's only one physical point
and this can be arbitrary
only when it's completely mixed
I'm very mistaken
the thing is
that M equals to 2
where we have the ball
that should still be rank 1
but for the picture it's not
is it probably because of dimension
the reason is because
the point is rank 0
but like
it's still the rank 1
so we need some other
quality saying that this should also be
better than
such other needs
it needs more than any
you can't depict it in two or three dimensions
that's the problem
I'm thinking more on
if you say this should work on the column
it should work on the column
yes
we have three point arcs where the dimension
is 1
and the dimension
that faces 1
so
I want to have
instead of
I just want to make sure it's just 1
that's true
can we
I mean it's been said aloud in words
but maybe the transcription
will save it
but Martin had the proof
in general possible imaginable
this is obvious to you
but not to me
so I would
we should write it down
maybe we should write it down
I can send you
my form of book
should be already for
arbitrary calls
this is just adapted to PST already
it's clear in the room
it's a projection to the interface
it's a good idea
I don't think every call has a projection to everything
I want
I'd like to be embedding the space
into the column
yeah because the space can be like
bigger
and then there's a small space
and I'm not exactly sure it's always exist
but that's another real statement
okay
if you have time
maybe we can just take my
I have it written down of course
and then we can adapt it to the
most
most general case
that would be cool
but I think it would be a
B
that's not the projection
but
that's the only thing we need to solve
we have your problem
I think RK
no just for everything
space
yeah the question is
if we already talk about giving up functions
I'm not giving in calls
how far are we away from
star
I think
every typical CSR of the brain
right
we don't have any
and also if you
give me the form of star
can we
give it to
the star
we're going to modify
the proof
this is the correct
way to start
VV plus E
notation game
yeah good
what's the next piece
of terminology that needs to be
defined
we need to talk about faces
we're going to be decoding up just one order
the table
okay so there's extra conditions
okay so then we need
a student
right
every
all the way
inside the interior
no you actually need to assume this for
V plus and every face
okay
and
that's what
faces would be possible
but finally
this is so far
but it's also very interesting the infinite
dimension right it's telling us what's
going to work and what isn't
and then so that these are the two assumptions
so far is this enough
I'm going to look through
and you will be necessary
so you can probably
come up with like notes that from all the
things that are supposed to be
okay so let's
assume that when we need it
so what's the map here what's the
place of five
so if you want to take a visible point
and you want to define the face
of that visible point
the easiest point to define a
face is to say that these are
all of the elements that could be majorized
by a positive order of height point
okay so I've just realized I need some more
notation right man this is just
the cone but we haven't sort of talked about
this kind of strange space C
yeah
so C is a sort of awkward
V
V plus such that
there is some
functional X
you call the A
the A-K on being
the B-J
on the D-J
and where
A-J
is in the other direction
right
then you have functional
okay so now we've got C
and now the point you made was
if we got to do
find the face
of your physical point
oh yeah we need to be in the background
so let X
be the point
yeah let X be the
point
and then
you see the curve
on the face of X
that's the
I would define this as the set of all elements
in D plus that you can majorize by X
my rule for X
set of all points
W
in D plus
such that
you can majorize
X
X is larger than
and by larger than we need your perspective
of course
by the way
is that common
knowledge that this is the face
I really have to
prove this for myself
but this is something that is
Alex came with the same question
so it seems like
I was
wondering because it sounded like
this condition is open in general
like
because you cannot majorize by zero
that's usually not an admissible point
if it's an open condition doesn't that
kind of contradict extreme faces
no
because the extreme face of the whole code
is one-dimensional
yeah okay
it's an extreme ray not an extreme
point
I see
but a nice way to think about this
is that it just tells you
that X can be decomposed
as one of
W divided by lambda plus
something else
yeah no I was just wondering
whether the face should always contain
the endpoints of every line as well
does that
still work?
yeah okay this still works
I see
yeah
yeah okay
no no okay I see
so it's in a sense you could say it's
like the smallest
face is the one
in the face of the point
is the one where the point is an interior
of the face
yes exactly
okay
because then it makes sense for a point
as well because then for a point
it's the only interior point of that point
okay
yeah but I think I convinced myself
yesterday that
I was happy with this definition
we found the face of X
a bunch of points in this cone
and this is now defining
5 right
the 5 is this map
the 5 of
the 5 is the
on the face
no you don't because
you can define the 5 on the whole of V
and you just say now I restrict
myself to this
yeah
so 5 is an
all of V
and it goes to just these constraints
where I work with something
here
one of
of
of V
so that's the element of R to the N
we're working
in the real numbers
mm-hmm
there's also each of those p-addict fields
and
and then 5 restricted
to
I want to
change the name
I think that
going
so
I'm restricted to add
these are the
step numbers
now
there's every function that's defined
so
so I'm going to use
on
and then the dimension of F
now is what sim R
is
mm-hmm
dimension
dimension of F
dimension of F is what
is an allergist to sim R
but we have to give it a
maybe we'll just call it in the F
mm-hmm
I should just think linear
a normal span of the
because it's called a zero so it's
we don't even have to give it a 5
so we can embed
a bit more space
so
F is a subcode
and so then D F
F
mm-hmm
F is a linear function
on a D F dimension of space
to an M dimension
space
okay this comes
through right so then we have
the rank now that
says the full dimension
it's dimper
what's the union
and I just
now I'm using
my brain the dim
sim
yeah this dim
and dimker is
the stuff that gets zapped
on F
and dim in
the end
or not end it's
it's more like equal then
there's a dim in
and then this is smaller equal
then
then dimker
right
then
then so we are done
no no no we still need this whole
move into the base
I don't want to fit on one board
ah
I should have written this more
it's not that people don't think the name
that comes from a thing
you may complain about this
um
but do we do
do we stick to just this feasibility case
or should we
make the
optimize what you say right
that's the game
the argument is a standard
programming argument right
feasibility equals optimality
it's just the same thing
I think
if you're from optimality I agree
but for everyone else
it's a pain
it's a footnote
okay
you say
it is obvious that
and then it's fine
you need to deal a bit
you're dealing differently with it right
on the one on one case you say okay
then I find another solution
with different rank on the other hand you say okay
if I find some D that is not
within the current
that is within the kernel of all A's
but not within the kernel of C
then I can find a phase that is actually
better
like has a better value
then
but okay
yeah but you can choose D
and you like
but you can only pick one
from the kernel of the constraint
right
the D has created the kernel
the D is from the kernel of the constraint
you cannot choose an example
but then you can still like DT
then you can still choose this
DT and you can walk in any direction of the T
without disturbing the constraint
but
only one
can prove it
it can be that you maintain
in the form for one direction
which will be grouped up to the regular
and you have to walk in the other direction
as the code implies then
was there exist D in the kernel
by it
such that
X which is now being
this is
minus
when that is satisfied
there really is something to be found
and you add it to the D
and then you walk
in
faced
how will you do that
in your algebra
where we are
because this thing is not going to work
so what am I missing
it's because
you're like
calling
assume
because the code is pointed
which we did
actually it was written up
and then
I think
in the code
the code contained
are real long
and those are not pointed because
you think the minus of the code is the real line
difference
okay
I'm going to write that
you'll say
this is the T circuit
okay
I would like to get the argument
there
so according to the code
is the code
and if you take the minus of the code
so you flip the sign of everything
and you take the intersection
that's only zero
but if you're copying the line
and you flip the sign of the line
it's nothing to itself
and the intersection of that code
with itself would be the line
okay
there
I think that's kind of cool
okay
and then now we're kind of done
right that was the end of it
well I know you have to argue that
therefore you can choose to be
okay
yeah there's not a Zonsla in this situation
so hopefully this is
there would be some unfortunately
from there right
in your box
that was weird wasn't it
but here
we have a line and we intersect it with the face
the intersection should be
well
zero
we have a line
that sometimes in the code
so it has to intersect some face
but probably it'll have a lot of page
okay
and we brought the problem
what
that's a geometry
okay
you have to get some help
to be looked up
but it's one of these
obviously true things that's probably
ridiculously true
yeah
and finite dimension is kind of easy
because you have
supporting hyper planes
I mean
it feels like a hyper plane separation argument
is going to help, it's going to be there
which makes it a Zonsla
argument in infinite dimensions
which is cool
let's fight
actually
if you use the separable space
you don't need Zonsla anymore I think
it's accountable
yeah
okay
how do we know that
finite
that's assumption
I mean this may be not right
in which case if you want to do iteration
it's probably not good
okay
if we use the same one
yeah
yeah yeah yeah
this argument is useless
if it's not finite
in which you use finite
should help right
it was here
it was here it was just written down
with a weasel
yeah
it has to be finite then for this argument to work
but that feels the opportunity
but I
I know
you can still go to a smaller space
and if it's infinite dimension
then you have an infinite regress right
so you
okay
but in this
proof you had
written already there the argument
was somehow about the number of constraints
why this phase was finite dimensional
because you would parametrize it by
the finite dimensional commutants
ah
so maybe that's where we do need the commutant
huh
but it feels like this shouldn't need that
still right now
let's play the game where the phase is infinite dimension
but
countably infinite like none of this weird
friggin
then you could just take the intersection
that you always go to a smaller space right
but then the kernel
the constraint development
it's huge
yeah it's okay
the phase is infinite dimensional
the problem is way way big
and I cannot just pick one existing point
but just
try something smarter
well just pick one random
and then you go down
and then you just take the infinite
you just keep there's an infinite regress
take the intersection over all these smaller
smaller phases
ximos
sorry
I was going to ask you a question
you have to
there could be
something at once there
you just have to take something out
so but then
there's something finite here
right it's not the dimension
of the kernel it's rather
the thing that you
the thing that you chop off
I mean you know that
the difference between
the phase dimension and the kernel dimension is finite
yeah right
yeah
so this sum off
but I mean in the C-style algebraic
case wasn't the argument that
assume you have no constraints
then
you just have a pure state which
and then you are somehow required that this is an exposed phase
and when you cut it
with another constraint
type of plane
and you somehow go up from like a one
dimensional thing to higher dimensions
that's why it remains finite
and you don't start with something that's
infinite dimensional when you have zero constraints
exactly that
I think we have to use this
in a sense so if there are
zero constraints this df
would not be infinite dimension
no
it's one dimension
I don't know what's the most general setting
where pure state
I mean where's
extreme point of a cone
when is
that
I mean is that always
one dimensional in a sense
or are there some pathological
logical settings
or
what's the extreme way it's going
come on
well let's summarize where we are right now
because we've gotten somewhere I think
yeah
if the world is finite dimensional here
it's all good right are we cool
are we cool
everything's infinite dimensional but df
is the dimension of this
face is finite then cool
right
so now we're into this slightly weird
zone where not weird
I mean maybe this is generic
where we should invert the argument
somehow when that's infinity
if we have a finite
rank solution
this finite rank cannot be bigger
yeah if we have a finite
rank solution then it cannot be bigger
so this works
I understood Alex's point
as to now we chose
at the moment chose x
arbitrarily
we should take anything to the point here
but maybe we have to be slightly
smarter in our initial choice
which is reasonable comment right
if you have any information use it
but chopping down
if I readily introduce
constraints you can maybe guarantee
but not
use the x
to add constraints
if you have no constraint
you just have the linear
intersection of the column
the optimal linear function
oh
yeah
there are many of them
at least one constraint
yeah
for me there's always one
because it's a state
yeah
your argument would be
if I had one constraint
my
the
dimension of the case would be
finite dimension
then I can find one
now I want to make sure that
I introduce new constraints
which could kick me out of that
I have to find another case
introduce constraints
maybe if you stick to the rank setting
you blow off the rank but say it's finite
introduce it again
it looks like it's 1230
usually
the time when people in this country
find it a good thing to do at the time
no I also need to do other things
I have this video recorded
I'll try it and just transcribe
it into a minimal tech
like this argument
a lot of this discussion can be just
dropped but
we'll see what happens
just that way that no one has the right
if that fails only though
it would be great
if someone takes a photograph and can reconstruct
this proof
I think I have my proof anyway
your proof is cool
like it's
I will just
maybe
that one
I mean it's super electrical
like it flies
and I'm not
totally joking about the one big PRL
but
what is the way
now should I
create an overlay as in the old times
or is it not going to be anything
Timo, old times
we don't do this anymore
that's why I'm asking
there'll be a github
do you know what
that's what I'm doing also
you can create an overlay
but connect it to github
I've been waiting
I've been waiting for this moment
I hate an overlay with a burning passion
yeah me too
but there are people who like to use it
yeah well they're going to learn that I hate
a burning passion
I would rather share on github
where you can check it out
it's sort of the only thing
make some kind of
make a call and make some kind of system
where he would go through the history of the github
repo and decide
like or there are authors based on the holy book
do you know what
I'm going to ask Claude when he transcribes this
who's the main author of them
very curious
I love him
that's why alphabetic is beautiful
actually
they called me to use certified random
certified random
yeah I would just like to use it
for my
we have access to real random
that's okay for you
if you don't need another thesis
I would like to use it
I need some fillery
my coat is more
cool
alright that was very interesting
thank you
thanks
bye
bye bye
yeah for sure